Is there something you're not telling me?
When we're in meetings together,
don't ever call my ideas "Ridiculous."
Come on. I'm being serious.
So am I.
Merrill's son asked for personal advice.
- And he picked you. - I know, right?
A surgeon needs to communicate. Can Dr. Murphy do that?
Can he do that under stress?
Can he do that knowing that a human life
literally hangs in the balance?
Thank you, Dr. Kalu.
You're welcome. It's a special blend.
I roast the beans myself.
Smells like leather.
Then none for you, Murphy.
I don't drink coffee.
It is dead in here.
That's why they call it the graveyard shift.
Oh, well, I call it paradise. You my trauma virgins?
Ah, Doctors Murphy, Kalu, Browne --
meet Dr. Audrey Lim,
your attending for the evening.
Coffee?
He roasts the beans himself.
Kiss ass.
E.R.
How long? Got it.
Listen up, everybody!
We got a mass cas coming in.
It's a bus crash, two dozen passengers.
Transfer all patients waiting for beds up to the nursing units.
Have maintenance bring down cots.
We're gonna convert the waiting room into triage.
No one goes home till we're all clear!
Page everyone on call. I don't care what department they are.
Tonight, everybody's trauma. Glove up and line up.
EMTs will have triaged onsite,
so the patients are gonna come in tagged.
I love these blank faces right before Armageddon.
Trauma color coding -- who knows it?
Green -- walking wounded. Yellow -- observation.
Red needs immediate attention.
And black go straight to the morgue.
All right, red tags, front of the line!
Red tags, front of the line.
Wedding bus blew a tire and flipped!
26-year-old female.
Second- and third-degree burns to her neck, chest, and left arm.
Kalu, you're up.
Trauma Six.
Guy was ejected 30 feet from the vehicle.
Multiple chest contusions,
acute respiratory distress on the scene,
sluggish pupillary response.
- How long have you been doing CPR? - 12 minutes.
- Have you shocked him? - Three times.
We got to crack him. Dr. Browne, I got this.
You take the next one. All right, Bay Five.
We secured the foreign object and staunched the bleeding,
but didn't want to touch it otherwise.
- Good thing. It nicked her carotid. - What is it?
Right now it's a little Dutch boy keeping her from bleeding out.
Pulse ox is dropping. She's at 87.
O2 sats down to 83.
Forget about the neck, Claire.
Treat her like any other patient.
What are the first steps?
Airway, breathing, circulation.
Good. Grab a kit.
I need help here! Somebody, help!
Murphy, go!
Let's go.
Trauma Three.
I can't stop the bleeding.
- He's bleeding out. - Do something.
I need a urinary catheter, 14-gauge needle,
arterial guide wire, occlusion balloon,
and 20 cc of saline, stat.
- What's he doing? - I have no idea.
Well, you don't have one, so I'm making a REBOA.
A what?
A REBOA.
Is that even a word?
A REBOA will occlude the damaged artery and stop the bleeding.
Release the pressure.
BP is stabilizing. 90 over 60.
Nice work, Dr. Murphy.
I made a REBOA.
Oxygen is dropping to 89.
All right. Light.
Open wide for me.
Throat's swollen from smoke inhalation.
Cric kit.
- Do you see soot in her mouth or nose? - No.
She doesn't need a cric. She needs an escharotomy.
Sats are going back up. 92 and rising.
Circumferential neck burns.
The shrinking charred skin is acting like a noose.
Escharotomy relieves the constriction.
Are you getting enough air now, ma'am?
Yes. Thank you.
Now get her out of this petri dish
and into an isolation ward in the burn unit ASAP.
Yes, sir.
Your heart's a bit muffled.
Am I having a heart attack?
No, but it's not completely good news.
Cardiac tamponade.
He needs a pericardiocentesis.
Yes, I'm aware of that.
18-gauge and 55 cc syringe, please.
We need a FAST ultrasound in here.
They're both in use.
You don't have imaging. You could puncture his heart.
Is the xiphoid in the same place as it was 20 years ago?
A REBOA.
Ballsy.
Could've gone really wrong.
Yes, well, it didn't.
It's a cowboy move --
something you would never even dream of trying.
How many times is Shaun gonna have to prove himself
before you give him a shot?
Dr. Rolendez, O.R. 6.
What happened in the E.R.?
Swan girl came in and you hesitated.
I wasn't hesitating. I was thinking of a game plan.
Murphy was thinking of the game plan.
You got overwhelmed.
I wasn't.
First trauma, it happens.
You have to think clearly, quickly, methodically.
You need to think a little more like Shaun.
A little more. Not identically.
How you doing?
Sorry.
Sorry. That's a stupid question.
You're maxed out on morphine.
I'll hold off until it reloads.
How bad is it?
We're making good progress.
I'll have to... debride any deroofed blisters
to prevent a secondary nosocomial and then --
I need a mirror.
It's the least you can do
since you can't even look me in the eye.
Oh, my God.
Do you know how many hideous $300 bridesmaid dresses
I've had to buy in the last two years?
I decided that when I got married,
my bridesmaids are gonna wear black cocktail dresses
so they can use them again, you know?
But now...
now I-I'm Freddy Krueger.
Who's gonna want to marry this?
I'm gonna find a nurse,
have her adjust your... your morphine drip.
Okay.
You hit your face.
Your jaw got stuck. It hurts.
So, this shot I just gave you is gonna knock you out
so that I can fix that.
Hang tight.
- Crash patients status check? - 23 people total.
One fatality on site, lost one in the E.R.
Examined all the red tags.
Got 13 yellow and green still in the waiting room.
- I'll take whoever's up next. - Marco Magallenes...
severed femoral artery, crushed femur.
I did the REBOA and then installed a temporary shunt.
Here are his CT and MRI results.
Find someone else for whoever's up next.
Oh, finally.
Excuse me. Are you Marco's family?
Yes.
We just found out that my cousin didn't survive the accident.
I'm sorry.
- It's a bit much. - I'm so sorry.
I'm Dr. Melendez, and this is Dr. Murphy.
I'm Ricardo.
I'm M-Marco's father.
This is, uh, his mother, Lorena, and this is Sonia.
They were getting married tonight.
How's my son?
Marco's femur was completely shattered,
and his lower leg isn't getting enough blood.
Can you save his leg?
Marco suffered too much bone fragmentation.
We can't fix it.
Our only choice is to amputate.
Mija.
Bay Five needs a grade three hyphema.
Head CT and page ophthalmology?
You read my mind.
Been a while.
How you holding up pulling an all-nighter?
I'll manage, but if you can find me a caffeine IV,
- Please move! - it'd be helpful.
- Tough night. - Yeah.
Thanks for coming.
It's part of the job.
So, when's the big day?
We haven't set it yet.
Oh, where is it gonna be?
We'll figure it out.
Maybe a beach somewhere.
We should talk about this later.
What? I like beaches.
If you have a more romantic idea...
My family likes churches.
We should talk about this later.
Dr. Lim, I think one of your yellows is about to turn red.
I've got my wedding all planned out.
I've got the dress, and I've got the flowers.
All I need is a groom.
You available, Dr. Murphy?
No.
You don't want some love?
No. No, I don't. I don't want love.
Dr. Glassman, neural consult, bay three.
Thank you.
I was here first.
Shaun.
Shaun!
My patient's scans are very important.
Well, my patient's important, too.
I need to see my patient's scans.
Is your patient pre-op or post-op?
Pre-op.
Okay, I'll give you the computer,
but you need to apologize first.
Okay, I'm sorry. Turn it on.
Why was Marco's family crying when Dr. Melendez
told them his leg would need to be amputated?
Well, their son's leg is about to be cut off.
It's sad. Crying is normal.
But when your options are amputation or death,
amputation is good news.
People need time to adjust to big changes.
Marco's family didn't even get a chance to pray for a miracle.
}It's not possible.
The bone damage is too severe.
A rod implantation won't work.
There's nothing to anchor into,
and the shunt won't last long enough to do reconstruction.
There are no other options.
What if we could replace the entire femur?
We're making him a new femur.
With a 3D printer?
3D-printed bones have only successfully been done with the mandible.
We know.
- That's a fairly small bone. - We know.
A femur has to support the weight of the entire body.
This one will be titanium. It can work.
It's an interesting idea...
but I need to think on it.
Right now we still got seven yellow tags waiting.
What do you have to think about?
- It's a good idea. - It's a brilliant idea.
The kid has brilliant ideas. That doesn't mean --
No, it was my idea,
and I'm aware of the risks --
infection, clotting, hardware failure...
Death.
- It wasn't your idea. - It was my idea!
And the risks are significant,
but isn't that their call?
- Don't we have to... - Maybe he said something,
and then you said something, and together, you --
My idea. Completely my idea.
The "brilliant" idea is 100% my brilliant idea.
Why is that a problem for you?
Maybe because I've known you for six months.
Every day we learn new things.
Today, you learned I'm brilliant.
The idea was brilliant.
And it was mine.
And if anyone can do this brilliant surgery,
it's you.
Flattery --
also brilliant.
Sleeping on the job?
Just needed some fresh air.
Feels like I'm suffocating in there.
She's in pain, spilling her guts out,
and every time I open my mouth,
I sound like an idiot.
Dr. Kalu -- unable to talk to women.
There's a first.
If you're not gonna be helpful, Claire, just leave.
You don't need to talk. Just listen to her.
You get to come out here, clear your head.
She's trapped in there,
alone with her thoughts, her fears.
You don't think she wants to get out?
You are her escape.
You want to put a fake femur into Marco's leg?
It's not fake. It's real.
It's not a real bone. We're making it out of titanium.
It's still real.
That's incredible.
And Marco will be able to walk, run, climb?
And swim.
Hopefully. That's the intention.
Well, have you done the surgery before?
- I haven't. - We'll be the first.
Well, nobody has ever attempted this surgery
with a bone as large as the femur.
I believe it's a viable option, but there are risks.
Risks? Could Marco die?
In my estimation, there's a 10% chance he won't make it.
Then no.
I'm not losing my son.
Wait. If there's a chance we can save Marco's leg,
we should at least discuss this some more.
That's what he'd want.
He'd want to live.
He'd want to have a life.
I know him.
He'd want to take the chance.
I will never forgive myself if Marco died
because I made a reckless decision.
Whose decision is this?
Does he have a healthcare proxy?
I don't know what that is.
When the accident happened,
were you on the way to your wedding or on the way back?
We were headed to the wedding.
Marco's parents are the next of kin.
They decide.
Please...
amputate our son's leg.
Murphy.
Why is the primary closure on the stump so vital in amputation surgery?
For a proper prosthetic fitting.
Why are you marrying Jessica?
Why does anyone get married?
I don't know.
I love her.
I don't understand why having someone to love
is so important to everyone.
You have to stand down.
- You can't amputate Marco's leg. - Why not?
I filed an emergency injunction to stop the surgery.
You were in a car accident.
Your neck was punctured.
The repair surgery went well.
You're gonna have to stay put for a week
before we can release you.
You're very lucky to be alive.
My wife, Jenna Hensel -- is she okay?
Can I see her?
She's not listed.
That's a good thing.
She's probably still in the waiting room.
I'll find her and bring her up.
She'll be relieved to know you're okay.
Okay.
What the hell am I supposed to do with an unconscious patient
whose leg is a ticking time bomb?
Judge Singh is en route.
She wants to hear from both parties and the doctors on the case.
I have to testify?
- Hopefully not. - Hopefully not.
I thought you would be happy.
You thought you could save the leg,
and I didn't want that not happening because the parents
are afraid to make a tough call.
It's their call to make.
And if the accident happened an hour later,
it would be the wife's.
And she wants the fake leg.
It's not fake.
I thought you didn't believe in just blindly following protocol.
He's their son.
Nobody's gonna love him more than them.
Seriously?
All parents love all children more than anybody else?
People get divorced all the time.
How often do they give up their kids?
So, if this was us,
you'd want your parents to decide over me?
- I didn't say that. - You kind of did.
I was saying, there needs to be rules,
that there needs to be bright red lines telling us
who gets to make these calls.
It's the parents' call.
Not anymore.
Now it's the judge's.
How much time does Marco have left on the temporary shunt?
Three hours,
and then his leg will die.
Okay.
Dr. Torture returns.
Thought I'd scared you off for good.
Pick a movie.
You deserve to get out of this room for a little while, too.
You think "Groundhog Day" is gonna make a difference?
"I'm torturing you, but, hey, you get to watch a funny movie."
That is sort of what I was going for, yeah.
I'm sorry.
I wish there was something else I could do.
How do you know there isn't?
This is protocol. This is what they teach us.
I lucked out.
I got the world's greatest expert on burn victims?
You know everything that can be done.
He loves to rock-climb, scuba dive, bungee-jump.
This is insane.
His leg is literally dying while we sit here reminiscing.
Please. We're trying to figure out what your son would want.
- He would want to live. - I want that, too,
but if there's a way that we can save Marco's leg,
he'd want me to do it.
Mija, Do you know what he wanted most of all?
He wanted to marry you.
He wanted to spend his life with you, have children with you.
Now, he can do all that.
He can be happy with a prosthetic leg.
He's young, and he's strong.
Mija, he can get through this.
- When we met -- - I don't care about your stories.
I don't care that you met rock-climbing
or kayaking or whatever.
- I just want -- - We met in rehab.
Hey, are either of you Jenna Hensel?
I haven't seen Jenna since we took pictures at the hotel.
But she got on the bus?
Yeah, she was sitting with Noomi.
I think she's still out there.
- Hey, guys! We've got to go back. - Where?
To the crash site. Now.
He never wanted you to know.
He's an addict.
He replaced one addiction for another one -- a healthier one.
- But he needs -- - What?
He needs to wakeboard or he'll drink himself to death?
- This is ridiculous. - No, it's not!
We talked about it a lot.
It's pretty much all you do in rehab.
Marco has clarity for the first time in his life.
He knows what makes him happy.
He knows his weaknesses.
He's not as strong as you think.
And that's okay, but --
Marco cheated on you.
It was about a month ago.
He was overwhelmed with the wedding and the planning.
He ran into an ex-girlfriend.
It only happened once.
You're lying.
You're upset that he had secrets from you, so --
No, she's not lying.
Mija, he -- he was -- he was so upset.
He does love you.
Okay, maybe we're digressing here a little bit.
And we really don't have the time.
It matters.
She doesn't know him like --
maybe none of us do, but...
but we are his parents, and you're not his wife. Yet.
Okay. Get the cops. Check everywhere --
other side of the road, bushes, trees.
If she was ejected from the bus,
she could be 40, 50 feet in any direction.
珍娜
Jenna!
我找到她了  我需要幫助
I found her! I need some help!
她腦出血了
Okay, she's got a brain bleed.
我們需要立刻帶她離開這里
We need to get her out of here now!
安德魯斯醫生
Dr. Andrews.
我認為塞拉斯可以勝任
I think Celez may be eligible
實驗性骨治療
for an experimental bone treatment.
說說看
Sell it to me.
我做了一些研究
Well, I've been doing some digging.
圣地亞哥社區醫院的燒傷科
San Diego Community Hospital's burn unit
在遵循一家巴西醫院的協議
has been following a Brazilian hospital's protocol
用羅非魚魚皮包裹燒傷部位
to wrap burns in tilapia skins.
我知道使用魚皮聽起來有點瘋狂
Now -- Now, I know fish skins sound a bit crazy,
但我覺得我們在這里也可以做
but -- but I was thinking we could do the same thing here.
卡盧醫生  你的想法很棒
Dr. Kalu, I applaud your thinking.
-但我們  -羅非魚皮所含膠原蛋白
- But we -- - Tilapia skins contain more collagen proteins --
比人類皮膚還多  一號三號都有
both types 1 and 3 -- than even human skin,
有助于修復組織
which aids in tissue repair,
-就不需要移植皮膚了  -卡盧醫生
- negating the need for grafts. - Dr. Kalu.
-并能加速皮膚恢復  減少  -卡盧醫生
- It's shown to accelerate healing, would reduce... - Dr. Kalu.
避免感染的風險并降低了病人切割皮膚之痛
the risk of infection and cut down on the patient's physical pain.
你說完了嗎  還是說你想再打斷我
Are you finished, or would you like to cut me off again?
我們這樣來  可以嗎
Okay, let's follow this through, shall we?
你得提出一個實驗性治療的可行建議
You have to come up with a proposal for the experimental treatment,
機構審查委員會通過之后
get it approved by our institutional review board,
你去提取醫學級別的羅非魚魚皮  然后再...
get your hands on medical-grade tilapia skins, and then we...
也許你可以幫助我加快進程
Well, I thought you could help expedite the process.
你認為我可以幫你從三個月減到兩小時
You think I could bring it down from three months to two hours?
你做完清創術了嗎
You finish the debridement?
-之后就交給我吧  -好
- Okay, I'll take over from here. - Okay.
掙脫思維定勢
Keep thinking outside the box.
有主動性是好事
Initiative is good.
我來了  給她使用呼吸氣囊
I'm in. Bag her.
你拿來電鉆了嗎
Did you get me the drill?
消防車上有  怎么回事
The fire truck had one. What's going on?
她的瞳孔擴張
Her pupil's blown.
她有硬腦膜下血腫
She has a subdural hematoma,
導致顱內壓增高
causing increased intracranial pressure.
如果現在不減壓
If I don't alleviate it now,
她肯定撐不到醫院
there's no way she makes it to the hospital alive.
好吧
Okay.
不省人事  女性  連枷胸
Unconscious female. Flail chest.
我得在現場鉆孔
I had to do a burr hole in field.
氧飽和度只有70多
Her sats are in the low 70s.
可以把她送去手術室了
She's good to go to the O.R.
硬腦膜下血腫
Subdural hematoma?
她有去大腦姿勢  左瞳孔擴張
She had decerebrate posturing, a blown left pupil.
當我用鉆頭在顱骨上鉆孔時
When I passed the drill bit through her skull,
涌出了一大堆血
a whole lot of blood pooled out.
做得好
Good call.
圣地亞哥社區醫院打來了
San Diego Community Hospital called.
他們在送羅非魚皮過來
They're sending the tilapia skins.
用救傷直升機送過來
They're medevacing them in.
一小時內能送到
Should be here within the hour.
塞拉斯...
Celez...
你符合一項實驗治療的標準
you meet the criteria for an experimental treatment
我認為這能讓你免受植皮手術之苦
that I think will prevent you from having to undergo skin grafts.
慢著  怎么會有這樣的事
Hold up. How did this even happen?
我發現圣地亞哥的試驗
Well, I found out San Diego's trial
允許多站點協作
allows for multi-site collaborations.
所以我們不用有自己的倫理委員會
So, there's no need for us to get our own I.R.B.
他們把皮給我們  我們提供病人數據
They give us the skins, we provide the patient data.
魚皮嗎
Fish skins?
羅非魚皮已經被清洗和殺菌
The tilapia skins have been cleaned and sterilized.
它們非常安全
They're perfectly safe.
你會做吧
You'll do it?
我會做
I'll do it.
干得好  卡盧醫生
Well done, Dr. Kalu.
干得好
Well done.
愿上帝助你
So help you God?
好的
Yes.
-梅倫德斯醫生可以告訴你  -他說了
- Dr. Melendez can tell you -- - He has.
但假股骨是你的主意  對吧
But the fake femur is yours, though, right?
-你對這個構思有多大信心  -不是假的
- How confident are you in its design? - It's not fake!
-肖恩  她想知道...-我知道她想知道什么
- Shaun, she needs to know -- - I know what she needs to know.
她需要知道能不能成功
She needs to know will it work.
她需要知道能維持多久
She needs to know how long it will last.
是的
Yes.
好吧
Okay.
他是他的醫生嗎
He's his doctor?
他是外科住院醫師  他很有天賦
He is a surgical resident. He's very gifted.
他會回答我的問題嗎
Is he going to answer my questions?
肖恩  我真的需要你專注
Shaun, I really need you to focus.
-馬爾科快沒時間了  -讓他回答吧
- Marco is running out of time! - Just let him answer!
不  我們已經知道答案了  他們不知道
No, we already know the answer. They don't know.
以前從未做過這種手術
This thing has never been done before.
安靜
Be quiet!
他的腳趾在變色
His toes are changing color.
動脈
受損
導致凝血
他在凝血  糟了  馬上呼叫梅倫德斯醫生
He's clotting. That's bad. Page Dr. Melendez stat!
-莫菲  什么情況  -血液分流在凝血
- Murphy, what do we got? - The shunt is clotting.
它在限制血流  它不行了
It's restricting blood flow. It is failing.
好吧  我們現在要做個決定
All right, we need a decision now.
要截腿還是換骨
Are we cutting off the leg or replacing the bone?
我相信馬爾科的父母和未婚妻
There's no doubt in my mind that Marco's parents
都很愛他  但現在顯然...
and fiancée all love Marco, but it's become clear --
現在給我個決定
Now. I need a decision now.
他是他父母的孩子
His parents know him as their child.
他是索尼婭的男人
Sonia knows him as a man.
換股骨
Replace the femur.
走吧
Let's go!
謝謝  謝謝
Thank you! Thank you.
-那就是出血  看見了嗎  -看見了
- And there's the bleed. See it? - Yes, sir.
你有夾過顱內動脈嗎
You ever clip an intracranial artery before?
沒有
No, sir.
來吧
Go for it.
每個第一次都一樣
Just like every first time --
你有點激動  有點惡心
you're a little excited, a little nauseous.
希望沒人受傷
Hopefully nobody gets hurt.
準備好了嗎
Is it good to go?
非常好
It's very good.
鉗子
Forceps.
你準備好了嗎
You ready?
是的
Yes.
確保夾子的利片不會碰到有孔動脈
Be careful the clip blades don't catch any perforated arteries.
我沒看見有血管擋著
I don't seen any vessels in the way.
那你還在等什么
Then what are you waiting for?
非常好
Very nice.
謝謝
Thank you.
沒有出血
Everything's dry.
道別完就蓋上去吧
Say goodbye and close the roof.
我們得在一分鐘左右
We need to get blood back into his leg
讓血流回他的腿
in the next minute or so,
否則我還是得做截肢
or I'm gonna have to amputate after all.
吊了胰島素  給他輸鈣
Insulin's hanging, loaded him with calcium.
盡我所能
Best I can do.
現在拿掉鉗夾
Let's release the clamps.
檢查毛細管充血
Check for capillary refill.
血流已修復
Blood flow is restored.
心電圖正常
EKG is normal.
金  我要聽到類似「變化」和「增量」的詞
Okay. Kim, I want to hear words like "Variability" and "Delta".
說給我聽
Give them to me.
我在耐心等待
I'm waiting patiently.
什么也沒有
I'm not getting anything.
給我看看
Show me.
檢查引線
Check the leads.
還是沒有
Still nothing.
也許是神經重塑
Maybe there will be some neuroplasticity.
她的大腦自己重新連接
Her brain -- I-it could rewire itself.
不
No.
沒有腦部活動
Zero brain activity.
我不知道為什么  但她去世了
I don't know why, but she's gone.
什么
What?
你的神經外科病人今晚死了
Your neurosurgery patient that died tonight --
有件事你該知道
there's something you should know.
什么
What?
馬爾科  我要你嘗試動動你的腳趾
Now, Marco, I want you to try and move your toes.
我不能
I can't.
他還好嗎
Is he okay?
我們不確定骨...
We're not sure if the bone --
他不會死吧
He's not gonna die?
他不會被感染吧
H-He's not gonna get an infection?
-他的身體不會排斥... -不
- His body's not gonna reject -- - No, no.
我們密切監控他
We're monitoring him very closely.
-最大的威脅... -他動了
- The biggest threat is behind -- - He moved.
他動了
He moved.
成功了
It worked.
有漫長的復原期等著你
You'll have a long recovery ahead --
好幾個月的物理治療
months of physical therapy.
不過現在  你應該好好休息
But for now, all you have to do is rest.
謝謝你
Thank you.
感謝你救了我的命  挽救了我的腿
Thank you for saving my life -- for saving my leg.
-謝謝  -不用謝
- Thank you. - You're welcome, sir.
準備好接著辦完我們的事了嗎
Are you ready to finish what we started?
先好起來再說
Get well first.
有的是時間辦婚禮
There's plenty of time for a wedding.
-謝謝  -不用謝
- Thank you. - You're welcome, sir.
謝謝
Thank you.
你看起來很好
You look good.
堅強  就像潛水俠
Tough. Like Aquaman.
我看起來像壽司
I look like sushi.
大家都愛吃壽司
Everybody loves sushi.
只需要六個月
It's only for six months.
你的新皮膚應該就能完全長好了
Your new skin should have completely grown in by then.
瘢痕應該會很小
Should have minor scarring.
謝謝
Thank you.
我誤會你了
I misjudged you.
你對我的評判很準確
You judged me just right.
她還在睡嗎
Is she still sleeping?
-你還沒告訴她嗎  -沒有
- You haven't told her yet? - No.
能出來一下嗎
Can I have a moment please?
當然
Of course.
你在事故現場發現珍娜后多久
How soon after you found Jenna at the crash site
給她插的管
did you intubate her?
幾乎是立刻就插了
Almost immediately.
我按壓她的胸骨
I did a sternal rub.
她表現出去大腦強直
She had decerebrate posturing.
她的左側瞳孔已經散大
Her left pupil was blown.
我知道她出現了硬膜下血腫
I knew she had a subdural hematoma,
所以我插了管  鉆了孔
so I intubated, did the burr hole.
并且她還有連枷胸
She also had a flail chest.
你插管之后檢查她的呼吸了嗎
Did you check her breathing after you intubated her?
查了
Yes.
我覺得我應該查了
Well, at least I-I think I did.
利姆醫生說珍娜到急診的時候
Dr. Lim told me that when Jenna came into the E.R.,
她的呼吸并不正常
she wasn't ventilating properly.
你插管插得太深了
You inserted the tube too deep
插進了她傷側肺的
into her right main stem bronchus
右主支氣管
of her injured lung.
我們沒法估計
We had no way of knowing
在給她做腦電圖前她已經缺氧了多久
how long she was hypoxic before we gave her the EEG.
我在她顱骨上鉆了一個非常完美的孔
I drilled a perfect burr hole into her skull
還是在夜里  在馬路邊
on the side of the road in the middle of the night,
但我  我插管卻插壞了
and I-I-I screw up her intubation?
是的
Yes.
即使是高年資醫生  當時的情況
It was tough conditions for anyone --
也是非常棘手的
resident or not.
我們任何人都有可能犯同樣的錯誤
Any one of us could have made the same mistake.
我曾經在急診室接診過一個女病人
I had a woman come into the E.R. once...
51歲  是個母親
a mother, 51 years old.
弗朗辛·帕克
Francine Parker.
她有兩個兒子
She had two boys.
她因為咳嗽來的
She had a cough --
很劇烈  但也不過是個咳嗽
a bad one -- but a cough.
我給她做了檢查
I checked her out,
給她開了點抗生素就讓她回去了
gave her some antibiotics, sent her home.
六小時后  她被人送來急診
Six hours later, she was rolled into the E.R..
她得了心臟病  我沒發現  結果
She had had a heart attack, and I missed it, and...
她死了
she died.
從那時起
Not one day...
之后我的每一天我都會想起她
goes by when I don't think about her.
她是你的第一例
She was your first.
其實  是第四例
My fourth, actually.
你不會忘記這種病例的
You're not gonna forget this.
永遠忘不了
You never forget.
但可能  下次遇到這些病例
But I don't know, maybe we're better off for it
我們可以做得更好
the next time around.
你得努力振作起來
You got to find a way to keep going.
回家去  去睡吧
Go home. Get some rest.
我都還沒有告訴她
I haven't even told her yet.
你不準去
You're not going to.
你犯了個錯誤  你與此事關系太大
You made a mistake. You're too close to this.
我不能讓你去和家屬
I'm not gonna allow you to talk to the family
或院外的任何人談論這事
or anyone else outside this hospital about this.
你聽明白了嗎
Do we understand each other?
明白
Yes, sir.
BGM: SETIN Sun by Mykl Lozin
♪ I don't have all the words to say ♪
♪ I'm still healing from my mistakes ♪
♪ I'll take the weight if it makes you stronger ♪
♪ I don't want to leave you in this place ♪
我給圣地亞哥社區醫院打電話謝謝他們
I called San Diego Community Hospital and thanked them
把我們納入他們的研究
for including us in their study.
他們說他們非常樂意接納我們
They said they were happy to do it.
并請我轉達對你的感謝
And they asked that I pass along their thanks to you
感謝你對他們燒傷科無比慷慨的捐款
for your very generous donation to their burn unit.
我知道你家里非常有錢
I know you come from a wealthy family.
我也不是嫉妒  但你
I don't begrudge that, but you...
不能每次病人有需要你就自己掏錢
can't open your wallet every time a patient's in need.
醫患之間的關系很快就會變味的
The lines can get real blurry real fast.
遵命
Yes, sir.
♪ Who am I to try and save you? ♪
♪ I ain't gonna hide ♪
♪ You have to fight today ♪
這是什么
What's this?
我的醫學委托人文件
My healthcare proxy.
杰西  不會有事的
Jess, nothing's gonna happen.
Really? That's good to know.
BGM: Once And For All by Lauren Daigle
♪ I won't let you down ♪
♪ No, no, no ♪
♪ But I won't let you down ♪
♪ I won't let you down ♪
♪ No, no, no ♪
Well, that was quite a night.
Been a doctor for a long while --
don't remember a night quite like that one.
Why did Nurse Farrar ask if I wanted love?
'Cause she's a nosy...
Shaun, you really don't want love?
I loved Steve and my rabbit.
Not anymore.
You don't love them anymore?
No, I don't. They're dead.
You can't love someone if they're dead.
Well, I've lost people I love.
I miss them, and it hurts, but I still love them.
I don't want love.
Okay.
You want breakfast?
Can I have four pancakes instead of three?
You can have five.
I only want four.
Okay.